dose.ca 2007-12-11

# CanWest Global Communications Corp.

**CanWest MediaWorks Income Fund  
CUSTOMER PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Date of original issue: September 7, 2005

**OUR COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY**  

CanWest MediaWorks Income Fund, CWMW Trust, CanWest MediaWorks (Canada) Inc. (the "General Partner"), CanWest MediaWorks Limited Partnership (the "Partnership") and the subsidiaries and affiliates of the Partnership or the General Partner (each, a member of "CanWest MediaWorks Group" and, collectively, the "CanWest MediaWorks Group") are committed to controlling the collection, use and disclosure of the personal information provided by its customers. 

This Customer Privacy Statement is a simplified version of the CanWest MediaWorks Income Fund Privacy Policy ("CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy") adopted by each member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group to ensure the accuracy, confidentiality and integrity of your personal information. 

The CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy is modeled after the Canadian Standards Association Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information and is compliant with federal and provincial private sector privacy laws including the federal Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act. A summary of the ten principles of fair information practices adopted in the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy is included at the end of this Privacy Statement. A complete copy of the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy is available on request by contacting your local Privacy Compliance Officer or on the CanWest MediaWorks Group’s website at [[www.canwestmediaworks.com](http://www.canwestmediaworks.com/)]. 

The application of this Customer Privacy Statement and the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy is subject to the requirements or provisions of any applicable legislation, regulations, tariffs or agreements (such as collective agreements), or the order of any court or other lawful authority. Various legal criteria independent of this Customer Privacy Statement and the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy will determine whether federal or provincial privacy legislation applies to the personal information that a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group collects, uses or discloses in respect of its customers or employees. This Customer Privacy Statement and the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy do not replace those criteria and nothing in these documents should be construed as indicating which privacy legislation, if any, applies to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information by the CanWest MediaWorks Group. 

**A SINGLE POLICY**

Any time you do business with a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group, or with anyone acting as an agent on our behalf, you are protected by the rights and safeguards contained in the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy.(Click here to download the full CanWest Privacy Policy in pdf format) 

**WHAT IS PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

"Personal information" is any information about an identifiable individual such as your name, residential address and e-mail address and includes information about your product and service subscriptions and usage, credit information and billing records, service and recorded complaints. 

Personal information is collected by the members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group only when you specifically and knowingly choose to provide it to us such as when you subscribe to a CanWest MediaWorks publication, enter a CanWest MediaWorks promotion or choose to receive information, products or services from a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group. We may also receive personal information from our business partners and other third parties provided that such third parties confirm to us that they have obtained your consent to the disclosure of your personal information. 

Publicly available information, such as a public directory listing of your name, address, telephone number and electronic address, may not be considered personal information. 

**COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

The members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group collect and use your personal information primarily for the purpose of providing you with the products and services you have requested from us, including the daily delivery of news and related content through CanWest MediaWorks print and online properties. 

Your personal information is used to communicate with you about your account and, with your consent, to provide you with information related to other CanWest MediaWorks publications and services. If you indicated that you were interested in receiving offers or information from selected CanWest MediaWorks sponsors or advertisers, your personal information would also be used to contact you or to send you e-mail materials and other mailings about products and services that might be of interest to you. You always have the option, however, to tell us not to share your personal information with other members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group or to exclude you from offers for other products or services. 

If you enter a contest or other promotion offered by a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group or on a CanWest MediaWorks website, your personal information will be used to administer the promotion, including the use of your name and selected other information for the purposes of contacting, announcing and promoting the winners of the promotion. 

The members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group may also contact you from time to time to conduct market research and surveys in an effort to continually improve our product and service offerings. 

Unless you specifically authorize us to release your personal information, or release is required or permitted by law, the CanWest MediaWorks Group will not sell, lease or trade your personal information to other third parties. 

Anonymous or "non-personal" information gathered by the CanWest MediaWorks Group through our websites may be used for technical, research and analytical purposes. Such information collected through surveys, existing files and public archives may be used by members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group to analyze their markets and to develop or enhance service offerings. 

Members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group will only ask for information about you that we need and will only ask for it when we need it. When we ask you for the information, we will explain to you why we need it and what we are going to do with it. 

We will seek your prior consent to the collection, use and disclosure of the information as required by applicable privacy legislation. Subject to legal and contractual requirements, you can refuse to consent to our collection, use or disclosure of information about you. You may also withdraw your consent to any further collection, use or disclosure of information about you at any time by giving us reasonable notice. If our intended disclosures or uses of information change, we will notify you accordingly. 

Your personal information will not be used for any other purpose without your consent. 

**DISCLOSURE**

To enable us to more efficiently provide the products and services you have requested from us, each member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group may share your personal information with other members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group and with selected third parties who are acting on our behalf as our agents, suppliers or service providers. Such other member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group and third party service providers are provided only with such information as is necessary in the circumstances (i.e. your residential address may be disclosed to our distributors and carriers for the purpose of delivering your daily newspaper subscription). Information provided to third parties may be used only for the purpose stipulated and is subject to strict terms of confidentiality. 

**USE OF COOKIES**

The CanWest MediaWorks Group use a browser feature called a "cookie" to collect information anonymously and track user patterns on CanWest MediaWorks websites. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a website. "Cookies" contain a unique identification number that identifies your browser, but not you, to our computers each time you visit one of our websites. Cookies tell us which pages of our websites are visited and by how many people. 

The use of cookies is an industry standard and many major browsers are initially set up to accept them. You can reset your browser to either refuse to accept all cookies or to notify you when you have received a cookie. However, if you refuse to accept cookies, you may not be able to use some of the features available on our websites. 

**ACCURACY**

Members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group will try to ensure that information about you is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, please inform the member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group to whom you provided your information of any change of name, address or other information. In the event you have questions about the accuracy of factual information we have collected about you, you will have access to that information in order to verify and update it. If we have disclosed inaccurate information about you to a third party, we will be pleased to contact the third party in order to correct the information. 

**SECURITY**

The CanWest MediaWorks Group is committed to protecting your privacy. Security measures, such as locked cabinets, restricted access and the use of passwords and encryption have been adopted to protect your personal information against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification. Our employees have been trained to respect your privacy at all times and those employees with access to your personal information shall use your personal information strictly in accordance with the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy and the laws applicable to each specific business. 

**ACCESS**

If you have any questions about the collection, use or disclosure of your personal information by a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group, or if you simply want to know whether we have any of your personal information on file, you may contact your local Privacy Compliance Officer. Except in limited circumstances, as specifically provided by applicable privacy legislation, members of CanWest MediaWorks Group can tell you whether they hold personal information about you. They can tell you the source of the information, allow you access to your personal information and find an account of the use that has been made or is being made of the information and the third parties to which it has been disclosed. 

The CanWest MediaWorks Group will only refuse access to information about you in those circumstances permitted or required by applicable privacy legislation. If a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group refuses access to you, it will provide you with the reasons for its refusal upon request. Exceptions may include information that contains references to other individuals, information that cannot be disclosed for legal, security or commercial proprietary reasons, and information that is subject to solicitor-client or litigation privilege. The CanWest MediaWorks Group will respond to your requests for access in accordance with applicable privacy legislation. 

**QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS**

If you have any questions or concerns about the personal information about you held by a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group or about the compliance by a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group with the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy, please contact your local Privacy Compliance Officer. Contact information for your local Privacy Compliance Officer may be found on our website or by contacting any of the members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group. 

Each member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group has procedures in place to receive and respond to complaints or inquiries about its handling of personal information. They will describe the complaint procedures to anyone who makes inquiries or lodges complaints. If you are not satisfied with the response from your local Privacy Compliance Officer after making a complaint, you may have recourse to additional remedies under applicable privacy legislation. 

For further information, please contact the federal Privacy Commissioner or your provincial Privacy Commissioner, as applicable. Contact information is available on our website or by contacting any of the members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group. 

**EXCEPTIONS, QUALIFICATIONS, AMENDMENTS**

Although not listed in this Customer Privacy Statement, the CanWest MediaWorks Group will rely on any exemptions or qualifications that are either set out in applicable privacy legislation or used by members of the CanWest MediaWorks Group in good faith, as permitted by law. This Customer Privacy Statement may be amended by the CanWest MediaWorks Group from time to time. 

**TEN PRINCIPLES OF FAIR INFORMATION PRACTICES**

**PRINCIPLE 1 - ACCOUNTABILITY**  
Each member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group is responsible for the personal information under its control and shall designate one or more individuals who shall be accountable for the member’s compliance with the procedures and principles set out in the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy and the attached Customer Privacy Statement or Employee Privacy Statement, as applicable. 

**PRINCIPLE 2 - IDENTIFYING PURPOSE**  
Each member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group will identify the purpose for which personal information is collected at or before the time the information is collected. The purposes for which information is collected, used or disclosed by a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group must be those that a reasonable person would consider are appropriate in the circumstances. 

**PRINCIPLE 3 - CONSENT**  
The knowledge and consent of the individual are required for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information, except where consent is not required by privacy legislation as, for example, where the collection, use or disclosure of personal information is solely for journalistic, artistic or literary purposes. 

**PRINCIPLE 4 - LIMITING COLLECTION**  
Each member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group shall limit the collection of personal information to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by such member. Personal information shall be collected by fair and lawful means. 

**PRINCIPLE 5 - LIMITING USE, DISCLOSURE AND RETENTION**  
Personal information shall not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the consent of the individual or as required or permitted by law. Personal information shall be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes for which it was collected. 

**PRINCIPLE 6 - ACCURACY**  
Personal information shall be as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used. 

**PRINCIPLE 7 - SAFEGUARDS**  
Personal information shall be protected by security safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. 

**PRINCIPLE 8 - OPENNESS**  
The CanWest MediaWorks Group shall make readily available to its customers and employees specific information about its policies and practices relating to the management of personal information. 

**PRINCIPLE 9 - INDIVIDUAL ACCESS**  
Upon request, an individual shall be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of his or her personal information and shall be given access to that information except where a member of the CanWest MediaWorks Group is permitted or required by law not to disclose personal information to the individual customer or employee. An individual customer or employee shall be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information disclosed to him or her and have it amended as appropriate. 

**PRINCIPLE 10 - CHALLENGING COMPLIANCE**  
An individual customer or employee shall be able to address a challenge concerning compliance with the principles in the CanWest MediaWorks Privacy Policy to his or her designated Privacy Compliance Officer. 

**THE CANWEST MEDIAWORKS GROUP**

* CanWest Global Communications Corp.  

* CanWest MediaWorks Inc.  

* CanWest MediaWorks Income Fund  

* Alberni Valley Times, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* Calgary Herald, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* CanWest Books Inc.  

* CanWest MediaWorks (Canada) Inc.  

* CanWest MediaWorks Limited Partnership  

* CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* CanWest News Service, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* Edmonton Journal, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* The Gazette, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* Leader-Post, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* Lower Mainland Publishing Group, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* Nanaimo Daily News, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* Ottawa Citizen, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* Pacific Newspaper Group, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* The Province, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* ReachCanada Contact Centre, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Limited Partnership  

* The StarPhoenix, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* Times Colonist, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* The Vancouver Sun, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

* The Windsor Star, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

Our Interactive Operations

* CanWest Interactive, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Publications Inc.  

Our Affiliated Print Operations

* The National Post Company.  

Our Affiliated Television and Radio Broadcast Operations

* CH Television, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Inc.  

* Cool FM, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Inc.  

* DejaView Partnership  

* FOX Sports World Canada Partnership  

* Global Television, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Inc.  

* Global Television Network Quebec Limited Partnership  

* Global Television Specialty Networks, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Inc.  

* Lonestar Partnership  

* Men TV General Partnership  

* Mobile Video Productions, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Inc.  

* Mystery Partnership  

* Prime TV  

* The Beat, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Inc.  

* Xtreme Sports Partnership  

Our Affiliated Sales Operations

* CanWest Media Sales, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Inc.  

* ReachCanada Contact Centre, a division of CanWest MediaWorks Limited Partnership  
CanWest Privacy Officers

To contact the privacy officers click the appropriate link below:
